# **Amy Beisel**



amybeisel@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/amy-beisel-685751148



7193311801



https://github.com/AmyBeisel

# **Summary**

I am lucky enough to have pursued some of my passions over the course of my career. As a forever-animal lover, I cared for my patients of all sizes in a small/large animal clinic as a vet tech for nearly 8 years. It's a heartwrenching job that ultimately led me to another passion - professional mountain biking. It took nearly a decade of dedication and sacrifice to win a National Title and represent the USA. After being one spot short of the Olympic long team, I decided to reevaluate my next chapter - Data Science. In college, I enjoyed math and science, especially statistics and genetics. I retired early at the top of my game to pursue a career in Data Science - currently working 4 part-time jobs and attending school 5 times a week every evening. In my next decade, I want to combine the skills that I have obtained throughout my life - hard work, empathy, commitment, and spirit - with my newly-honed expertise in Data Analysis, Machine Learning, and Computer Science. I am also embarking on an entrepreneurship journey as a beekeeper, establishing my brand, High Altitude Hives, successfully selling out my first harvest! Check out my Linkedin profile to see my first Data Science project about the decline of bee colonies.

# **Experience**



# Student

Lambda School

Oct 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month +)

Lambda School is an 18 month long, mastery-based full-stack data science program.

Demonstrated mastery in the following subject areas:

- Python (pandas, numpy, seaborn, scikit-learn, matplotlib)
- Predictive analytics & exploratory data analysis
- Feature engineering, clustering, dimensionality reduction
- Productization and cloud deployment
- SQL (PostgreSQL), Elasticsearch, AWS (Lambda, Elastic Beanstalk), Flask, FastAPI, ETL pipelines
- Natural Language Processing, Recommendation Systems
- Tree ensembles, neural networks, gradient boosting, ensemble methods



#### **Head Beekeeper**

#### **High Altitude Hives**

May 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months +)
Inspect multiple hives and check colony health
Constructed a bear-safe apiary with electric fencing
Extract honey safely for harvest
Packaging, placement, and promotion
Winterize hives for the season



#### **Professional Mountain Bike Athlete**

Self Employed

Jul 2012 - Aug 2019 (7 years 2 months)

Compete at a National and International level
Podiumed over 100 times, including a 2018 Marathon National Championship win
Organize a traveling/training schedule
Help support sponsorship with social media/trail advocacy
Volunteer with group rides, non-profits

# Vete

# Veterinary Technician

Gunnison Valley Vet Clinic Jul 2015 - Dec 2015 (6 months)

# **Veterinary Technician**

# Town & Country Animal Hospital

Jul 2009 - Jul 2015 (6 years 1 month)

In-Patient Medical Care - Place IV catheters, Blood draws, administer medications

Anesthesia - incubate, monitor patients vitals, assist the doctor in surgery

Dentistry - clean, scale, polish

Laboratory duties - blood smears, urine sediments, fecal

Client communication

Technician appointments - Blood work, toenail trims, anal glands

Small and large animal care

Clinic technician - check-in appointments

Prepare prescriptions

Assist with reception



# Receptionist

#### **GUNNISON VALLEY FAMILY PHYSICIANS**

May 2007 - Feb 2008 (10 months)

# **Education**



# Western Colorado University

Bio-Psychology, Biology, Psychology 2002 - 2006



# Lambda School

**Data Science** 

2019 - 2021

#### Skills

Data Analysis • Python (Programming Language) • Machine Learning • Data Visualization • Computer Science

#### **Honors & Awards**



# **Elite Marathon National Champion**

May 2018